D/S Dylan S. Spangler

Junior Software Developer

- +-765-615-6069

- Linkedin.com/in /dylan-spangler
- Zoom: 571-821-3623
- % Github.com/d-spangler

ABOUT ME

After graduating from college, I returned to my high school and coached the football team. Shortly after the season ended, I began a career in retail...

What I had intended to be a stop-gap job slowly became a burdgeoning career. I quickly worked my way up at the store level and spent 5 years with Lowe's before I needed a change of scenery and a new challenge – one that would emplore my impulse to think critically and flex my creative muscles. That led me to Eleven Fifty's immersive Software Development program.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts in Communication

DePauw University – Greencastle, IN August 2010 – May 2014

Software Development

Eleven Fifty Academy
March 2020 — June 2020

TECH SKILLS

C#

HTML/CSS

ASP.NET

Object Oriented Design

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Service Manager

Lowe's Home Improvement / Anderson, IN / January 2018 – January 2020

Maintain the direct reports of the Appliances, Cabinets, and Millwork departments

- Coach the staff to improve customer service and increase sales
- Identify issues regarding product availability, service issues, associate training, and facilities while simultaneously working towards swift and effective resolutions

Receiving Clerk

Lowe's Home Improvement / Anderson, IN / June 2017 – January 2018 (Promoted)

Oversee the receiving process of a \$40 million/year business

- Focus on shipment accuracy, efficient scheduling, and safe receiving processes
- Resolve logistical issues concerning direct-from-vendor and intra-company shipments via effective communication, orchestration of corporate processes, and overall product knowledge

Department Manager

Lowe's Home Improvement / Anderson, IN / September 2016 – June 2017 (Promoted)

Manage the direct reports of the Flooring department

- Develop and orchestrate a training regimen on new installation services software
- Coach associates on product knowledge and customer interaction skills

D/S Dylan S. Spangler

Junior Software Developer

- +-765-615-6069
- dylan.spangler.is@gmail.com
- Linkedin.com/in /dylan-spangler
- Zoom: 571-821-3623
- % Github.com/d-spangler

HOBBIES & INTERESTS

I love to play tabletop games, D&D being a personal favorite. I also love reading, writing, and spending time with my wife, 3 dogs, and 2 cats. I enjoy using D&D as a creative vehicle for my writing. I also love Call of Cthulhu among others. Travel is also a passion of mine. While in college I went abroad twice – visiting China on the first trip and visiting the Netherlands, Austria, and the Czech Republic on the second. My wife and I have dreams of potentially living abroad one day, or at the very least traveling every chance we get.

PERSONALITY

DISC Assessment

Very high C and S, low I, and very low D

Myers-Briggs

INFJ-Turbulent

SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Project Management

Collaboration

Problem Solving

Critical Thinking

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Sales Specialist

Lowe's Home Improvement / Anderson, IN / April 2016 – September 2016 (Promoted)

Serve as the store expert in the Millwork department

- Drive sales through regular, direct customer interactions focusing on installations and specialty sales
- Create and maintain customer relationships

Installation Coordinator

Lowe's Home Improvement / Anderson, IN / January 2015 – April 2016 (Promoted)

Manage installations from time of sale through completion

- Establish project timeline with customer and communicate any updates with said timeline
- Address installation issues accordingly with installation contractors
- Oversee contractor payment upon project completion

Assistant Football Coach

Anderson High School / Anderson, IN / July 2014 - December 2014

Responsible for the development of the team's Offensive Line

- Organize and manage team practices, walkthroughs, and other miscellaneous activities as determined by the Head Coach
- Identify and resolve schematic and personnel issues "self-scouting"